<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Pankaj K Mishra</title>
    <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Pankaj K Mishra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pankajkmishra.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Solving Inverse Problems to Training Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/post/2025/02/04/from-solving-inverse-problems-to-training-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/post/2025/02/04/from-solving-inverse-problems-to-training-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>From Solving Inverse Problems to Training Neural Networks Step 1: Define the Model The neural network predicts house prices using:&#xA;$$ \hat{y} = w \times \text{Size} + b $$&#xA;where:&#xA;$ w $ is the weight (to be optimized), $ b $ is the bias (to be optimized), $ \text{Size} $ is the input feature (house size in square meters), $ \hat{y} $ is the predicted price. Step 2: Initialize Parameters We start with random initial values:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Being a Coauthor</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/post/2024/10/17/the-art-of-being-a-coauthor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/post/2024/10/17/the-art-of-being-a-coauthor/</guid>
      <description>The Art of Being a Coauthor So You Have Been Invited to Be a Coauthor—Congratulations! Most likely, even before contributing to the writing, you’ve already played a significant role, perhaps by providing key data, technical expertise, or essential resources. This is a rewarding moment, as it signifies that your contribution is recognized and valued. However, with this recognition comes a responsibility to support the progress of the paper or proposal. In reality, most of the writing and heavy lifting is carried out by one or two lead authors, who are often PhD students or postdocs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>For an up-to-date list, visit: 🎓 Google Scholar 📄 Three-dimensional inversion of gravity data using implicit neural representations&#xA;Pankaj K Mishra, Sanni Laaksonen, Jochen Kamm and Anand Singh.&#xA;Arxiv Priprint: arXiv:2510.17876, 2025.&#xA;📄 Lithosphere in digital twins of the Earth&#xA;Pankaj K Mishra Geophysical Journal International 242(2), ggaf199, 2025.&#xA;📄 Stochastic joint-inversion of seismic and controlled-source electromagnetic data&#xA;Pankaj K Mishra, Adrien Arnulf, Mrinal K Sen, Zeyu Zhao, and Piyoosh Jaysaval.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>✨ MULTIVERSE - Multiphysics inversion and uncertainty estimation (2024 - 2026) Your browser does not support the video tag. MULTIVERSE is a project that will develop methods and technologies for stochastic multiphysics inversion and uncertainty estimation for geophysical data, leveraging modern high-performance computing (HPC) and scientific machine learning (SciML). The project aims to revolutionize the resolution of geophysical challenges by advancing data extraction techniques. By integrating physics-based knowledge into machine learning, MULTIVERSE reduces reliance on large datasets and enables fast, reliable predictions for parameter inference, uncertainty estimation, and data integration, even with limited, noisy, and multiscale geophysical data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>&#xA;Inversion of Geophysical Data (Instructor) &amp;mdash; spring 2024 🏛️ University of Helsinki&#xA;Seismic Methods of Prospecting Laboratory (TA) &amp;mdash; autumn 2014, 2015, 2016 🏛️ Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur&#xA;MATLAB for Geoscience (Workshop) &amp;mdash; 2014, 2015 🏛️ Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
