<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Pankaj K Mishra</title>
    <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Pankaj K Mishra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pankajkmishra.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Being a Coauthor</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/post/2024/10/17/the-art-of-being-a-coauthor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/post/2024/10/17/the-art-of-being-a-coauthor/</guid>
      <description>The Art of Being a Coauthor So You Have Been Invited to Be a Coauthor—Congratulations! Most likely, even before contributing to the writing, you’ve already played a significant role, perhaps by providing key data, technical expertise, or essential resources. This is a rewarding moment, as it signifies that your contribution is recognized and valued. However, with this recognition comes a responsibility to support the progress of the paper or proposal. In reality, most of the writing and heavy lifting is carried out by one or two lead authors, who are often PhD students or postdocs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>For an up-to-date list, visit: 🎓 Google Scholar Three-dimensional inversion of gravity data using implicit neural representations&#xA;Pankaj K Mishra, Sanni Laaksonen, Jochen Kamm and Anand Singh.&#xA;Arxiv Priprint: arXiv:2510.17876, 2025.&#xA;Lithosphere in digital twins of the Earth&#xA;Pankaj K Mishra Geophysical Journal International 242(2), ggaf199, 2025.&#xA;Stochastic joint-inversion of seismic and controlled-source electromagnetic data&#xA;Pankaj K Mishra, Adrien Arnulf, Mrinal K Sen, Zeyu Zhao, and Piyoosh Jaysaval.&#xA;Geophysical Prospecting,73(6) e70043, 2025.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Physics-based machine learning for geophysical inversion Stochastic inversion, uncertainty estimation and joint-inversion Your browser does not support the video tag. Large-scale 3D magnetotelluric modelling &amp;amp; inversion D-Rex, funded by ERA-MIN2 under Horizon 2020, has concluded its work and is now in the reporting phase. The project advanced the understanding of mineral systems through geophysical data from Sweden, Norway, and Finland, integrating it into a unified Common Earth Model (CEM). Key efforts included electromagnetic surveys, 3D modeling, and machine learning techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>Lead developer &amp;amp; maintainer of Julia Geophysics organisation.&#xA;MTGeophysics.jl &amp;mdash; A software repository for magnetotelluric geophysics research and applications NodeLab &amp;mdash; Node-generation and adaptive refinement for testing, and implementing various meshfree methods (including physics-informed machine learning) for solving PDEs in arbitrary domains </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pankajkmishra.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Courses &amp;amp; Workshops Inversion of Geophysical Data (Instructor) &amp;mdash; University of Helsinki | 2024, 2026 Seismic Methods of Prospecting Laboratory (TA) &amp;mdash; Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur, India | autumn 2014, 2015, 2016 MATLAB for Geoscience (Workshop) &amp;mdash; Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur, India | 2014, 2015 PhD Students Naimatullah (Co-Supervisor) &amp;mdash; Department of Earth Sciences, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay Fareeda B. S.(Co-Supervisor) &amp;mdash; Department of Geophysics, Indian Institute of Petroleum and Energy Masters Students Eetu Hyppiö (Supervisor) &amp;mdash; University of Oulu </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
